Hanchett, Walter Papers 6120
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Photocopies of articles with notes on Cortland, popular culture, ethnic groups, religion, arrests of Reds, includes newspaper clipping and bibliographical file. Book. From Many Roots, Cortland County Chronicles, Volume 4, 1986.. (Box 9)
  - First Congregation Church Photos, 1991-1992 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    Contains photographs, late 1991 to early 1992
  - grand Jury Action of 28 Jan. 1920 and Disposition of these cases (Box 9, Folder 17)
    28 Jan. 1920
  - Deportations and Cancellations, 1920 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    Post early 1920 to end of 1920
  - Slavic Community, 1921 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Liberty Bonds and Bail, 1920 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    23 March 1920
  - Train, bus and streetcar schedules and Railroad Info, 1919 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    Contains "Rails North" magazine
  - Night School, Americanization Classes, Materializations, 1914-1933 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Focus on 2nd and Later Generations (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Public Schools Teacher 1925-1929 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - School Honor Lists, 1930-1935 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Athletic Activates, 1931-1935 (Box 9, Folder 26)
    Also 1938-1939
  - High School Graduation, 1928-1934 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - College and post-High School Education, 1944 (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Upward Mobility, 1949-1955 (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Publication References (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - 'From many Roots", 1986 (Box 9, Folder 31)
    Cortland County Chronicles Volume 4
  - Bibliographical Research References (Box 9, Folder 32)
    Large box of all notecards, organized
- Photocopies of articles with notes and clippings on Socialism, radical labor, ethnic unions, Ukrainian American unions, National Labor Party. Copies of articles on the Lusk committee, Communism, Red Scare, 1919, Russia, US-USSR relations. Bibliographic. (Box 10)
  - Reference Guides, 1986-1992 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    October 10, 1986, among others
  - Newspapers and Magazines NY Times Index July 1918 - Dec. 1920, 1918-1920 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    July 1918 - Dec. 1920
  - Newspaper and Magazines NY Times Index July 1918 - Dec. 1920, 1918-1920 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Documents (Box 10, Folder 4)
    One document, 1919
  - General, 1984-1991 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Rand School (Box 10, Folder 6)
    1992, among others
  - Socialist Party and Movement Connected with It, 1967-1988 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Socialism - Local and Radicalism, 1919-1978 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - American Federation of Labor in Cortland, 1993 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    11 May 1993
  - IWW (Box 10, Folder 10)
    1972, among others
  - Anarchism - Sacco and Vanzetti, etc., 1991-1992 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Union of Russian Workers and related Organizations (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Communist parties and Left Wing Movements (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Ukrainian-American Communism/Socialism (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - National labor Party, 1919-1925 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Fronts, 1919-1921 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - 1897 Census of Kiev Gubernica (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - 1919 In General (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - W Section of Chapt. 1 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Wickwire Search (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Overman Committee (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Campaign for Shorter Work Week, 1989 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Willing to be Deported, 1919 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Ron Lewis' Footnotes on Allied Blockade of Russia and Cordon General File, 1919-1968 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - US in Siberia During Civil War, 1919 (Box 10, Folder 25)
    The Independent 16 Aug. 1919
  - US-USSR Cold War and Foreign Intervention (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - AE Stevenson, 1919 (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - "The Lusk Committee", 1971 (Box 10, Folder 28)
    Timmins, Kathleen; April 12, 1971
  - Lusk and Committee (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Lusk Committee, Continued, 1919 (Box 10, Folder 30)
    1919, among others
  - Truth about the Lusk Committee, 1920 (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - "Loyalty and legislative Action" (Box 10, Folder 32)
    Chamberlain, NY State Legislature, pgs. 1-53 and 203-215
  - "American Communism" (Box 10, Folder 33)
    O'Neal and Warner, Chapters II-V, Xeroxes
- Bibliographical file on index cards.. (Box 11)
  - Europeans in Cortland (Box 11, Folder 1)
    Large box of notecards, other sources
  - Notecards of Russians (Box 11, Folder 2)
    Set of notecards with the names of Russians, addresses
  - Chronological File of Red Scare Events 1898-1923 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    Stack of notecards
  - Pamphlets (Box 11, Folder 4)
    Loose stack of pamphlets, notecards, etc.
  - Notecards (Box 11, Folder 5)
    Large box of notecards with Source names, titles.
- Biographical file, with photocopies of articles, clippings, and notes, A-M.. (Box 12)
  - Military Conscription Act of May 18, 1917 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Industrial Directory of NY (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Biographical Sketches of Members of Congress, 1774-1971 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Abercrombie, J. W. (John W.) (Box 12, Folder 4)
    With Quotes from 1920
  - Anderson, G. W. (George W.) (Box 12, Folder 5)
    Judge in Colyer v Sheffington, with quotes from 1920
  - Walter H. Angell, 1994 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    Work fro Humane Society; Fall 1994
  - Balch, Emily Greene (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Baldenkoff, Ivan "or Burgdorff or whatever his true name" (Box 12, Folder 8)
    Also known as Georgieff.
  - Berger, Samuel A. (Box 12, Folder 9)
    Deputy NY State Attorney General who worked Lusk Committee.
  - Britt, Connell, 1919-1920 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    Also contemporary newspaper clipping
  - ILR Interview with George Britt 22 July 1985 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    22 July 1985
  - Nancy Britt Scudamore, 1982 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    With 6 Nov. 1979 Obituary
  - Brooks, Lawrence Graham, 1919-1920 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Buck, A.J. of Cortland (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Burke, Frank (Box 12, Folder 15)
    Assistant Director and Chief of Dept. of Justice or Bureau of Investigation
  - Canillus Cutlery, 1991 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    Dec. 1991
  - Caminetti, Anthony (Box 12, Folder 17)
    Commissioner General of Immigration in June 1919 released on 1 June 1920
  - Capasar/Capasin, Efrin (Box 12, Folder 18)
    Reference materials regarding 1919-1920
  - Chrisman, frank (Box 12, Folder 19)
    2 Jan. 1920
  - Chunic/Chiman/Chemir, Ivan (Box 12, Folder 20)
    Information from 1919
  - Clark, Pauline (Box 12, Folder 21)
    Organizer for Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America
  - Cosmos Club, 1920 (Box 12, Folder 22)
    April 1, 1920
  - Darrow, Charles (Box 12, Folder 23)
    Quote form 1919-1920
  - DeSilver, Albert (Box 12, Folder 24)
    A or the director of the "Civil Liberties Union" in March 1919
  - Dunn, Robert W. (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Ezel, M. (Mike) (Box 12, Folder 26)
    Regarding events in 1919 10th and 25th of October
  - Finch, R. W. (Box 12, Folder 27)
    "Chief Investigator" for the Lusk Committee. Established the intelligence operation that "had agents reporting on numerous radical groups and individuals" Josephson, 134
  - Fish, Walter (Box 12, Folder 28)
    12 and 20 December 1919
  - Flynn, William J. (Box 12, Folder 29)
    "Director, Bureau of Investigation" signature to the letter from him "To all Special Agents and Employees of Dept. of Justice, 12 Aug. 1919
  - Garvan, Francis Patrick (Box 12, Folder 30)
    Regarding events in 1919 relating to Palmer and the bombings
  - Georgieff, Ivan B (Box 12, Folder 31)
    See Baldenkoff
  - Goldberg, Lewis, 1984 (Box 12, Folder 32)
    US Attorney in Colyer Case
  - Gregory, Thomas W. (Box 12, Folder 33)
    U.S. Attorney General before Palmer
  - Grenchenko/Grinchenko/Green/Renchenko (Box 12, Folder 34)
    many documents from 1920, but others from other dates
  - Griffith, Thomas L., 1983 (Box 12, Folder 35)
  - Gundlach, E.T. or Grundlach (Box 12, Folder 36)
    Offered $10,000 to Post in early 1920 to help him in defense against impeachment
  - Hale, Swin Burne (Box 12, Folder 37)
  - Hard, Wm. (Box 12, Folder 38)
  - Hoover, J. Edgar (Box 12, Folder 39)
  - Howe, Frederic C (Box 12, Folder 40)
  - Hrikorash/Hirkorash/Harikorash, Jacob (Box 12, Folder 41)
  - Hughes, Charles Evans (Box 12, Folder 42)
  - Ivashtchenko/Wasitchenko/Evashtchenko/Ivashtzhenko, Nikifor/Nikifer/Nicifor/Nickifor (Box 12, Folder 43)
  - Mary Kabanuk Interviews, 1985 (Box 12, Folder 44)
    July 1 and 9, 1985, also 1 Feb 1985
  - Mary Kabanuk Interviews, 1984 (Box 12, Folder 45)
    2 Oct. 1984
  - Mary Kabanuk Interviews, 1984 (Box 12, Folder 46)
    11 Sept. 1984
  - Interviews with Mary Kabanuk by Nancy Brilt Scudamore, 1984 (Box 12, Folder 47)
    Ny NBS July 1984; by WH 11 and 24 July 1984
  - Kabanok/Kebanuk/Kabanuk/Kebanik/Kebanick/Rebanisk/Kchanuk, Ivan (Box 12, Folder 48)
  - Karpenko, Sam (AG) and Family (Box 12, Folder 49)
  - Kelleher, George E. (Box 12, Folder 50)
  - King, Carol Weiss (Box 12, Folder 51)
  - Klein/Kline, Irvin/Irwin/Ervin, 1919 (Box 12, Folder 52)
    December 5, 1919
  - Kostenko, Stevne/Steve (Box 12, Folder 53)
  - Larienko, Lavrenenko, and variants (Box 12, Folder 54)
  - Litokovitch/Litonovitch/Litonovich/Litonvisch/Litvinovich, Louis (Box 12, Folder 55)
  - Lowe, Caroline (Box 12, Folder 56)
  - Mary Lucy Interviews, 1984 (Box 12, Folder 57)
    8 August 1984
  - Lusk, Clayton Riley, 1980 (Box 12, Folder 58)
    April, 1980
  - Macovetski/Macovitzki/Mikosiewicz/Macovetzki/Macow, John (Box 12, Folder 59)
  - Makovetsky, John and Jim and Sam (Box 12, Folder 60)
    Mackel, Mackow, Makashecskii; see also Polinsky
  - Makovetsky, Arksenty (Box 12, Folder 61)
  - 1914-1921 Directories (Box 12, Folder 62)
  - Martens, LCAK, 1919 (Box 12, Folder 63)
    March 1919
  - Martin, Isaac (Box 12, Folder 64)
  - Miller, Nathan (Box 12, Folder 65)
  - Morton, John, 1917-1923 (Box 12, Folder 66)
  - Morton, John Continued (Box 12, Folder 67)
- Biographical file, with photocopies of articles, clippings, and notes, N-Z. Index card records of photo albums A,B,C,D,E,P,K. The actual photo albums are accessible at the Cortland County Historical Society, Cortland, NY.. (Box 13)
  - Nelles, Walter (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Neritzky/Nerutzky/Nerucky, John (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Newton, Charles D. (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Nightwine, L.S. (Box 13, Folder 4)
    Minister at First Congregational Church
  - Nolan, 1964 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    Justice agent in Boston in May 1920; May 13 1964
  - Palmer, A. Mitchell (Box 13, Folder 6)
    Concerning 1920
  - Povlenko/Polenko/Pavlenko/Povisnko, Efim/Efin (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Povlosky/Polonsky/Polinsky, Romen/Pimen (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Post, Louis F. (Box 13, Folder 9)
    became Acting Secretary of labor 6 March 1920
  - Recht, Charles (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - "Russian Club" and Orchestra (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Russian Cooperative Grocery (Box 13, Folder 12)
    Grocery across from Wickwire Brothers
  - Russian School, 1914-1916 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Ruthenberg (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Shevchenko/Sgevebenko/Shevanko, Ivan, 1920 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Scudamore (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Skeffington, Henry J., 1918-1920 (Box 13, Folder 17)
    Commissioner of Immigration for Boston
  - Somers, Lee, 1919 (Box 13, Folder 18)
    February 24th, 1919
  - Starr, J.H., George W., George J, 1919 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Steimer, Mollie (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Stevenson, Archibald E., 1919-1984 (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Stilson, 1902-1910 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Stoklitsky, Alexander, 1957 (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - Suter, J.T., 1919 (Box 13, Folder 24)
    25 November 1919
  - Tormey, James C., 1918-1919 (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - Trevor, John B., 1919-1925 (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - Wallis, Frederick A. (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - West, William J. (Box 13, Folder 28)
    assistant in charge of radical activities for Boston Office of Department of Justice
  - Wickwire Family (Box 13, Folder 29)
    Contains photographs of the Wickwire mausoleum
  - Wilson, William Bauchop, 1920-1942 (Box 13, Folder 30)
  - Winslow, Gertrude, 1982 (Box 13, Folder 31)
    Tony Gengarlby sees possible link to Colyer case and/or Elizabeth Glendower Evans, if I understood him correctly by phone, 30 Sept. 1982
  - Zmry/Zamry/Zamryk/Zemry, Nick (Box 13, Folder 32)
  - Album "A" (Box 13, Folder 33)
    Contains photographs of Cortland's Ukrainian families
  - Album "B", 1999 (Box 13, Folder 34)
    Contains photographs (Britt, Halitsky, Kabanuk Families); November
  - Album "C", 1999 (Box 13, Folder 35)
    Contains photographs of The South Side Community; November
  - Album "D", 1999 (Box 13, Folder 36)
    Contains photographs from the collection of Helen Cincotta; November
  - Photo Data Cards, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 37)
    January 2000
  - Album E and P,K Listings, 1999 (Box 13, Folder 38)
    November 1999
  - NA (Box 13, Folder 39)
- Biographical file, three tapes with interview of Daniluk, now moved to media case, are boxes 39,40,41. Research notes on Daniluk family.. (Box 14)
  - Notecards (Box 14, Folder 1)
    Name cards
  - Adamovich/Adamoski (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Antonuck, 1928 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    4/24/1928
  - Baranowski, 1982 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    16 June 1982
  - Berardi (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - berehovoy, 1915 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - beresavsky, 1925 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Berkwitz (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Bondarenko (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Bottoff (Box 14, Folder 10)
    Contains photographs of graves
  - Boyer (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Bozda (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Branistine or Variant (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Britt, Ewsey and Family, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    July 1981 Interviews
  - Budzinski (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Buicko, James and Mary (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Bustoff, 1924-1926 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Cervola, 1933 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Cherenvol (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Chuprini/Cheabrina (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Clish (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Comnick (Comnich?) (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Coocher, 1933 (Box 14, Folder 23)
    April 12 1933
  - Curiok (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - Cusharenko (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - Dadman (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - Dashnik (Box 14, Folder 27)
  - Docenko (Dosenko), 1910-1915 (Box 14, Folder 28)
  - Drach, 1994-1996 (Box 14, Folder 29)
    Apparently post WWI; contaisn photographs of graves
  - Dugan, Mike (Dudan), 1987 (Box 14, Folder 30)
  - Efimenko, 1989-1996 (Box 14, Folder 31)
    With photographs of graves
  - Fadik, 1929 (Box 14, Folder 32)
  - Fedshuk/Fedchik, 1921-1986 (Box 14, Folder 33)
  - Ferric (Box 14, Folder 34)
  - Figorsky, Figursky (Box 14, Folder 35)
  - Finkelstern or Finkelstein (Box 14, Folder 36)
  - George, O.K., 1919-1942 (Box 14, Folder 37)
  - Ginfkoske (Box 14, Folder 38)
  - Goss (Box 14, Folder 39)
  - Graham (Box 14, Folder 40)
  - Greenman, 1902 (Box 14, Folder 41)
    19 June 1902
  - Gurich (Box 14, Folder 42)
  - Halitsky/Halisky/Lucey Halsey and variants, 1984-1993 (Box 14, Folder 43)
  - Hanga, Fred, Sr. and Jr., 1986 (Box 14, Folder 44)
  - Edward Healey, 1941 (Box 14, Folder 45)
  - Holler (Box 14, Folder 46)
  - Hongrey (Box 14, Folder 47)
  - Hormansky (Box 14, Folder 48)
  - Ivanenok, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 49)
    15 July 1981
  - James (Box 14, Folder 50)
  - Kadick (Box 14, Folder 51)
  - Jenin, 1994 (Box 14, Folder 52)
    February 5 1994
  - Kaliliec, 1986-1994 (Box 14, Folder 53)
    25 Aug. 1986; contains photographs of grave
  - Kaplan (Box 14, Folder 54)
  - Karpenkos (Non-Arrest Group), 1995 (Box 14, Folder 55)
    21 Aug. 1995
  - Karpenkos, 1917-1988 (Box 14, Folder 56)
  - Kasperek, 1990 (Box 14, Folder 57)
    12 Oct. 1990
  - Killan (Box 14, Folder 58)
  - Kingdeski, 1930 (Box 14, Folder 59)
    25 march 1930
  - Kirichenko, 1913-1989 (Box 14, Folder 60)
  - Kleivo (Box 14, Folder 61)
  - Miss Kob, 1914 (Box 14, Folder 62)
    February 27, 1914
  - Koltun (Box 14, Folder 63)
  - Koslovko, 1915 (Box 14, Folder 64)
    4/9/1915
  - Kostinek (Box 14, Folder 65)
  - Kozlowski (Box 14, Folder 66)
  - Keezmenker (Box 14, Folder 67)
  - Lathin, 1979 (Box 14, Folder 68)
    4 August 1979
  - Lebed, 1980 (Box 14, Folder 69)
  - Leserk/Lesnik, 1921 (Box 14, Folder 70)
    May 2 1921
  - Levchenko, 1930 (Box 14, Folder 71)
    15 Sept. 1930
  - Lipman (Box 14, Folder 72)
  - Litka, 1906 (Box 14, Folder 73)
    7/11/1906
  - Lukaszewicz, 1995 (Box 14, Folder 74)
    Sept. 18 1995; Contains photographs of graves
  - Mandubura, mandibura, mandabura, 1941 (Box 14, Folder 75)
    15 May 1941
  - Maniaci, 1990 (Box 14, Folder 76)
    11 December 1990
  - May, 1913 (Box 14, Folder 77)
    September 16 1913
  - Mazuk (final variant of Maizuk and Moiseiczik), 1986-1994 (Box 14, Folder 78)
  - McCarthy/McCarty (Box 14, Folder 79)
  - Dr. McGraw (Box 14, Folder 80)
  - Mehann, 1995 (Box 14, Folder 81)
    15 September 1995
  - Merkle (Box 14, Folder 82)
  - Mikocurch (Box 14, Folder 83)
  - Milesko/Milsko, 1996 (Box 14, Folder 84)
    30 July 1996
  - Miller/Mellar, 1924 (Box 14, Folder 85)
    5/28/1924
  - Millman, 1920 (Box 14, Folder 86)
    20 January 1920
  - Moiseichik, 1945 (Box 14, Folder 87)
    15 Jan 1945
  - Muskavitch, 1979 (Box 14, Folder 88)
    16 August 1979
  - Muskovin/Moskovin, 1925 (Box 14, Folder 89)
    September 14 1925
  - Nadvorsky/Nodrosky and variants, 1925 (Box 14, Folder 90)
  - Nesmick, 1930 (Box 14, Folder 91)
    21 July 1930; 15 September 1930
  - Nikitenko, 1979 (Box 14, Folder 92)
    26 November 1979; Contains photographs of grave
  - Odinek (Box 14, Folder 93)
  - Ondrako, 1990 (Box 14, Folder 94)
  - Orimenko and variants (Box 14, Folder 95)
  - Osadchy and Variants (Box 14, Folder 96)
  - Owego Street School (Box 14, Folder 97)
  - Parchomenko, Parkomenko, Parchoemenko, and Variants, 1946-1994 (Box 14, Folder 98)
  - Patrick, John and Family (Box 14, Folder 99)
  - Pavlenko, Efrim (Nick Polanko's parents), Polanko, and variants, 1941-1986 (Box 14, Folder 100)
    1986 Interviews
  - Pawlosky, 1984 (Box 14, Folder 101)
    27 October 1984; Contains photographs of graves
  - Peltz (Box 14, Folder 102)
  - Philipenko, 1986 (Box 14, Folder 103)
  - Piaseczny (Box 14, Folder 104)
  - Pohajanko, 1986 (Box 14, Folder 105)
    25 July 1986
  - Poradosky, Paradowsky, and variants, 1933-1947 (Box 14, Folder 106)
    20 March 1933; Aug 1947
  - Printz (Box 14, Folder 107)
  - Pushkar, 1982-1988 (Box 14, Folder 108)
    21 Oct. 1988; 21 May 1982; Contains photographs of graves
  - Romanko, 1986 (Box 14, Folder 109)
    November 1986 Interviews
  - Rosco, 1918 (Box 14, Folder 110)
  - Rosen (Box 14, Folder 111)
  - Rosenberg (Box 14, Folder 112)
  - Saschenko (Box 14, Folder 113)
  - Samosuk, 1942-1961 (Box 14, Folder 114)
    9 Nov. 1942; 28 Nov. 1961
  - Schafranek, 1990 (Box 14, Folder 115)
    May 10 1990
  - Scherbina, 1945-1988 (Box 14, Folder 116)
  - Scovel, 1912-1985 (Box 14, Folder 117)
  - Senchinko, 1965 (Box 14, Folder 118)
    Dec 30 1965
  - Shapoval, 1986 (Box 14, Folder 119)
    12 may 1986
  - Shechenko, 1924-1926 (Box 14, Folder 120)
    Oct 20 1924; 10 Aug 1926; 12 July 1926
  - Shostok, 1915-1988 (Box 14, Folder 121)
  - Shrebtienko, 1945 (Box 14, Folder 122)
    6 Jan 1945
  - Shulman (Box 14, Folder 123)
  - Simister/Kaschak, 1986 (Box 14, Folder 124)
    November 20, 1986
  - Simon (Box 14, Folder 125)
  - Sjoez (Box 14, Folder 126)
  - Smithkin (Box 14, Folder 127)
  - Smolar/Small (Box 14, Folder 128)
  - Sokurenko/Zacurenko/Sourenko/Sournko, 1917-1995 (Box 14, Folder 129)
  - Solomon (Box 14, Folder 130)
  - Soshinsky, 1994 (Box 14, Folder 131)
    15 March 1994
  - Soltieykow, Joseph (Box 14, Folder 132)
  - Midwife Mrs. Spano (Box 14, Folder 133)
  - Spillman (Austria) (Box 14, Folder 134)
  - Sprandoff (Box 14, Folder 135)
  - Still (Box 14, Folder 136)
  - Stipenko (Box 14, Folder 137)
  - Stout (Box 14, Folder 138)
  - Stupke (Box 14, Folder 139)
  - Terletzky (Box 14, Folder 140)
  - Torkos/Oros, 1987 (Box 14, Folder 141)
    July 9, 1987
  - Tsyganenkov, 1916 (Box 14, Folder 142)
    Russian and English; May 30 1916
  - Tucci, 1986-1996 (Box 14, Folder 143)
    Jan 11 1996; Sept. 2 1986
  - Turko (Box 14, Folder 144)
  - Ududak (Box 14, Folder 145)
  - Uhlir (Box 14, Folder 146)
  - Vanek (Box 14, Folder 147)
  - Waas, 1995 (Box 14, Folder 148)
    Sept. 22 1995
  - Wasilenko, 1962-1996 (Box 14, Folder 149)
  - Wereshak (Box 14, Folder 150)
  - Wilbur (Box 14, Folder 151)
  - Wolkov (Box 14, Folder 152)
  - Yaichuk, 1968-1996 (Box 14, Folder 153)
  - Yuradi, 1920-1926 (Box 14, Folder 154)
  - Zahnko (Box 14, Folder 155)
  - Zaichenko and Variants, 1931 (Box 14, Folder 156)
    27 April 1931; Contains photographs of graves
  - Zatrimiski (Box 14, Folder 157)
  - Zeleznajak (Box 14, Folder 158)
  - Zemanek, 1992-1998 (Box 14, Folder 159)
  - Zetchinko, 1931 (Box 14, Folder 160)
    27 April 1931
  - Zimmerman (Box 14, Folder 161)
  - Zivotosky, 1927-1979 (Box 14, Folder 162)
  - Zowadenko and Variants (Box 14, Folder 163)
  - Polinsky/Polonsky, 1988 (Box 14, Folder 164)
    Russian and English; Contains map
  - Makow Family Letters (Box 14, Folder 165)
  - Pamela Purple Papers, 1915-1988 (Box 14, Folder 166)
  - Patrick Data, 1992 (Box 14, Folder 167)
    Russian and English; contains map
  - Mazur Data (Box 14, Folder 168)
    Contains Map
  - Patrick Project Pictures (Box 14, Folder 169)
    Russian and English; Contains photocopies of photographs
  - Local History: Patrick Village Area (Box 14, Folder 170)
  - Patrick Photos (Box 14, Folder 171)
    Contains photocopies of photographs
  - Patrick Documents (Box 14, Folder 172)
  - Khmelnitsham (Box 14, Folder 173)
    Russian and English; contains maps
  - Shostakora (Box 14, Folder 174)
  - Patrick (Box 14, Folder 175)
  - Daniluk (Box 14, Folder 176)
    Contains a photograph of a family; 2 magazines; one cassette tape labeled "Interview with Jean N. van Buskirk; and one cassette tape labeled "Interview Initiated by Barbara Woods"; one address book
- Naturalization records and census, vital statistics.. (Box 15)
  - Petition for Naturalization (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Naturalization Forms: Masters and Models (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Third Page (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Declaration of Intention for Naturalization (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Certificate of Arrival (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - The Foreign Born Population of Cortland (Box 15, Folder 6)
    Thomas L Hyder
  - Residential Location by Country of Origin (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - "Foreign Born Population of Cortland" (Box 15, Folder 8)
    Hyder, Thomas L. Contains maps.
  - General Information on Local Immigration and Naturalization (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Name Lists of W Slavic Workers, 1914-1916 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Cortland Population From Russian Empire, 1910-1915 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Name Lists of Cortland's Population from Russian Empire, 1914-1916 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    Working file for W Employees
  - Lists of Persons Involved 1919-1923 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Reports of Communism- General of Immigration, 1905-1906 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - County Agricultural Censuses 1917-1918 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - 1900 Federal Census Cortland County, 1910 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Cortland County Employees (Box 15, Folder 17)
    Notecards
  - Residents and 1920 Census (Box 15, Folder 18)
    1920 census on Microfilm
  - 1920 Census Blank Forms (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - 1920 Census Forms (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - 1910 Federal Census (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Sources of Population Data on Cortland County, 1995 (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - 1915 Census (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - 1915 Census data and Notes (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - General Information on 1925 Census (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - Cortland County Slavic Surnames in WH Files (Box 15, Folder 26)
  - CC Graduates Who Stayed in Cortland (Box 15, Folder 27)
  - General Survey of Populations in Central NY Early 20th Century, 1941 (Box 15, Folder 28)
  - Soundex Guide (Box 15, Folder 29)
  - Vital Statistics of Cortland, 1909-1912 (Box 15, Folder 30)
- Photocopies of articles and notes on individuals and Hoover investigation in Coyler case. Frankfurter-Brandeis-Chafee connection.. (Box 16)